ul.ie 2019-06-15

# Privacy Statement | UL - University of Limerick

The University of Limerick fully respects an individual’s right to privacy and actively seeks to preserve the privacy rights of those who share information with the University. Any personal information which is volunteered to the University will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1988 and Data Protection (Amendment) Act, 2003. This statement is not deemed to be a contractual undertaking.

## University of Limerick - Website Privacy

This Privacy Statement explains the privacy guidelines that the University of Limerick has adopted for its websites. This policy relates to websites hosted under the ul.ie domain only. The University is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of external websites. Within the UL domain one may find websites over which the University has no editorial responsibility or direct control. At times, links to these websites are not always clearly identifiable. Such sites can include the websites of student organisations etc. While UL encourages compliance with this web privacy statement at such sites, please consult the privacy statements of individual sites or contact the persons responsible for those sites, in order to understand the policies and practices under which they operate.

## Processing of personal information on website

The University of Limerick does not collect any personal data about web visitors on this website. Information provided is used by the University only in accordance with the purpose for which it has been provided and will only be retained for as long as required for the purpose. The University of Limerick will not retain any personal information about its web visitors on this website without permission save in cases where the University is required by law to do so, such as the investigation of a criminal offence by the Gardai, or a breach of the University’s web-related policies, procedures or guidelines.

## Processing of technical information on website

This website does not use cookies, apart from temporary "session" cookies which enable, for example, a visitor’s web browser to remember which pages on this website have already been visited. Visitors can use this website with no loss of functionality if cookies are disabled from the web browser.

Technical details in connection with visits to this website may be logged on the University’s server for accounting and auditing purposes (e.g. Computer IP number). It is the policy of the University not to disclose such technical information in respect of individual website visitors to any third party unless obliged to disclose such information by a rule of law. The technical information will be used only for statistical purposes.

It should be noted that technical details, which the University cannot associate with any identifiable individual, do not constitute "personal data" for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1988 and Data Protection (Amendment) Act, 2003.

## Review

The University of Limerick has adopted this Privacy Statement for its websites. The University reserves the right to review and amend this statement at any time without notice in light of legislative or other requirements and the statement should be accessed regularly for the most up to date Privacy Statement.

##  Further Information and Contact Details

Further information on data privacy rights is available on the University’s website [www.ul.ie/dataprotection](http://www.ul.ie/dataprotection) and the website of the Data Protection Commissioner [www.dataprotection.ie](http://www.dataprotection.ie/). Please contact the Information and Compliance Office at the University of Limerick on queries relating to the processing of personal data on this Website.  
Email: [dataprotection@ul.ie](mailto:dataprotection@ul.ie) or Phone: 061 234393
